Chris McGahan

Pleasant Grove, UT · 435-592-4027

sirhc17@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrismcgahan/

Summary

Business-minded, infrastructure-literate, full-stack programmer with 10+ years of experience building and maintaining web apps. Forward-thinking consultant, practiced at advising primary stake holders through design, prototyping, and implementation of new applications and software features. Generous collaborator, who provides constructive feedback, picks up on critical concerns, and excels at creating tools and architecture that simplify the day-to-day work of team members.

Skills

 $PHP \cdot SQL \cdot JavaScript \cdot React \cdot Flux \cdot Node.js \cdot Linux \cdot Nginx \cdot Apache \cdot AWS \cdot Docker \cdot ASP.NET \ C\# \cdot Java \ Git \cdot Code \ Review \cdot Kanban \cdot Direct \ collaboration \ with \ stakeholders$

Professional History

Senior Software Developer, Rock Solid Internet Systems, Inc.

Dec 2014 - Present

- Currently operating as primary architect for PHP/MySQL application and routinely engaging in development of React/Flux font-end
- Participating in refinement of work prior to acceptance in development backlog
- Managing production servers, load balancers and auto-scaling groups on AWS platform
- Managed said infrastructure through doubling of shipping volume in 2020
- Managed client who was developing a custom carrier solution, acting as primary support, developer, and technical advisor while facilitating upwards of 200,000 shipments per month
- Integrated with USPS, created parcel sorting software deployed in multiple warehouses, and built custom
 tracking solution to track packages across multiple airlines and through the USPS system which required the
 unification of non-standard data such as air cargo confirmation emails
- Executed the creation of a hosted development environment for new and existing team members using Ubuntu, Nginx, Docker, and VS Code Remote, resulting in the reduction of setup time for new developers from days to hours and eliminating the need to choose between debilitating query latency and the need for regular data downloads that took hours to complete

Web Developer, Online Web Marketing / St George News

Sep 2013 - Dec 2014

- Developed custom plugins and themes for small business sites built on WordPress
- Built new features for an ecommerce site built on OpenCart including new checkout flow, and music preview feature for the songs and albums sold on the site
- Built classifieds system for cars on St George News
- Built custom calendar supporting community submissions, repeating events with complex rules, and multiple view layouts

Full Time Missionary, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints

Aug 2011 - Aug 2013

Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2008 - Aug 2011

Built websites and applications for small businesses using PHP/MySQL/jQuery/WordPress

- Built a Real Estate site that integrated with the local MLS allowing the agent to keep visitors on her website
 while viewing listings from other agents and brokers
- Created a lodging directory with listing management portal for lodgers near Brian Head Resort

Web Programmer, Southern Utah University

May 2007 - Jun 2009

- Developed ASP.NET applications in C# with Access and Microsoft SQL databases
- Created Housing Finder to connect students with off-campus housing options and allow owners to manage rental inventory
- Created Travel Authorization System for University faculty and staff, which streamlined the process of getting travel approved and reimbursed, and completely replaced the paper forms previously used for this purpose

Other Projects

Local Booking Firm

Sep 2018 - Present

- Provided emergency maintenance on custom CRM built on Rails and deployed via AWS Elastic Beanstalk
- Stepped in to assist in development of new CRM, which required heavy modification, including overhauling
 intake forms, integrating with multiple credit card processors, creating workflows for one-time and recurring
 billing, and adding file management system which uses S3 for document storage
- Successfully migrated sales agents and clients to new CRM allowing the company to move forward and continue the development of new features
- Continue to provide consulting and assistance with cloud server resources

Pro Membership Sweepstakes

Sep 2016 - Present

- Met with owners to determine project requirements and offer technical consulting
- Developed custom CRM and migrated existing members to new system, which includes features like email reminders, customizable reports, member referral tracking, member waiting list, and integration with Stripe credit card processing and billing
- Met with owners to offer technical consulting and modify functionality while facilitating growth from around 200 members to club imposed cap of 2,500

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Computer Science

Southern Utah University, Dec 2010

- Principle programming language was Java
- Won Bronze Medal for Computer Programming in national SkillsUSA competition

Certification

A+ Certified Professional

CompTIA, May 2006

References

References available upon request